Guide to the William Sloane Coffin, Jr. Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Additional Material, 1918-1996; Accession 2004-M-009
  - Writings
    - Books
      - Sermons
        - Riverside years: Riverside Church [unless otherwise noted]
          - "The Christmas Message", 1983 December 25 (Box 23, Folder 532)
          - "Fast Away the Old Year Passes...", 1983 December 31 (Box 23, Folder 533)
          - "Epiphany Lessons", 1984 January 8 (Box 23, Folder 534)
            See also: Accession 2004-M-056, 1916-2003 Box 26
          - "Follow Me!", 1984 January 22 (Box 23, Folder 535)
          - "The Nations are One Blood", 1984 January 29 (Box 23, Folder 536)
          - "The Year of the Human", 1984 February 5 (Box 23, Folder 537)
          - "Lincoln's Birthday", 1984 February 12 (Box 23, Folder 538)
          - "Love your Enemies", 1984 February 19 (Box 23, Folder 539)
          - "The Transfiguration", 1984 March 4 (Box 24, Folder 540)
          - "Temptations", 1984 March 11 (Box 24, Folder 541)
          - "Young Abraham", 1984 March 25 (Box 24, Folder 542)
          - Untitled, "What makes Easter so exciting is the cosmic quality of it...", 1984 April 22 (Box 24, Folder 543)
          - "Where's the Love?", 1984 May 20 (Box 24, Folder 544)
          - "Let Us Press on to Know God", 1984 July 1 (Box 24, Folder 545)
          - "White Harvests, Few Repairs", 1984 July 8 (Box 24, Folder 546)
          - "The High and Long Road", 1984 July 15 (Box 24, Folder 547)
          - "Not Peace, But a Sword", 1984 July 22 (Box 24, Folder 548)
          - "In Praise of Rest", 1984 July 29 (Box 24, Folder 549)
          - "Homecoming Sunday", 1984 September 23 (Box 24, Folder 550)
          - "Religion and Politics", 1984 September 30 (Box 24, Folder 551)
            See also: Accession 2004-M-056, 1916-2003 Folder 235
          - "The City", 1984 October 7 (Box 24, Folder 552)
          - "EMC: A Sermon on the Amount", 1984 October 14 (Box 24, Folder 553)
          - "Stewardship in the Public Realm", 1984 October 21 (Box 24, Folder 554)
          - "Reformation", 1984 October 28 (Box 24, Folder 555)
          - "Why Christian Education?", 1984 November 11 (Box 24, Folder 556)
          - "World Food Sunday", 1984 November 18 (Box 24, Folder 557)
          - "Born a Child that We Might Grow Up", 1984 December 2 (Box 24, Folder 558)
          - "Abounding in Hope" [probably Riverside, but location uncertain], 1984 December 9 (Box 24, Folder 559)
          - "Abiding in Love", 1984 December 16 (Box 24, Folder 560)
          - "Jesus-Not 'Answer' but 'Presence'", 1985 January 6 (Box 24, Folder 561)
          - "Life is a Gift", 1985 January 20 (Box 24, Folder 562)
          - Untitled, "If not three, then two cheers at least for the man often referred to as the rich young ruler..." [location uncertain], [1985 March 10?] (Box 24, Folder 563)
          - "To Run and Not to Grow Weary", 1985 March 24 (Box 24, Folder 564)
          - "God was in Christ", 1985 March 31 (Box 24, Folder 565)
          - "Despite Appearances, It is an Easter World", 1985 April 7 (Box 24, Folder 566)
          - "Parable of the Sower", 1985 April 21 (Box 24, Folder 567)
          - Peace Within Our Walls - And Without, 1985 April 28 (Box 25, Folder 568)
          - "Two Sermons that Address the Issue of Homosexuality": "On Human Sexuality" [by Channing E. Phillips] and "The Fundamental Injunction: Love One Another" [by Coffin], 1985 May 5, 12 (Box 25, Folder 569)
          - "The Flame of Creativity vs. the Fires of Sin", 1985 May 26 (Box 25, Folder 570)
          - "The Pharisee and the Publican", 1985 June 2 (Box 25, Folder 571)
          - "No Vengeance", 1985 July 7 (Box 25, Folder 572)
          - "Thirsting for Righteousness", 1985 July 14 (Box 25, Folder 573)
          - "Salt of the Earth", 1985 July 28 (Box 25, Folder 574)
          - "I Will Do You Good", 1985 September 22 (Box 25, Folder 575)
          - "Flying in Unity" [page 5a is possibly unrelated], 1985 September 29 (Box 25, Folder 576)
            See also: Accession 2004-M-056, 1916-2003 Folder 286
          - "The Liberty of the Restored", 1985 October 6 (Box 25, Folder 577)
            See also: Accession 2004-M-056, 1916-2003 Box 27
          - "Worthy of our Steeple", 1985 October 13 (Box 25, Folder 578)
          - "Converting the Purse", 1985 October 20 (Box 25, Folder 579)
          - "Coming to Terms with Death", 1985 November 3 (Box 25, Folder 580)
          - "The Noneconomic Uses of Money", 1985 November 10 (Box 25, Folder 581)
          - "The Love of Power", 1985 November 17 (Box 25, Folder 582)
          - "The Ultimate Optimism", 1985 December 8 (Box 25, Folder 583)
          - "Loving in the Manner of Christ", 1985 December 15 (Box 25, Folder 584)
          - "God Bless the Cheerful", 1985 December 22 (Box 25, Folder 585)
          - "The Tooth that Nibbles at the Soul", 1986 January 5 (Box 25, Folder 586)
          - "After Christmas", 1986 January 12 (Box 25, Folder 587)
          - "AIDS", 1986 January 26 (Box 26, Folder 588)
            See: Accession 2004-M-009, 1918-1996 Folder 675
          - "Guardian Vessels of the Spirit", 1986 February 2 (Box 26, Folder 589)
          - "The Point of Lent", 1986 February 16 (Box 26, Folder 590)
          - "Unfriendly, but Loving", 1986 February 23 (Box 26, Folder 591)
          - "A Spiral of Joy", 1986 March 2 (Box 26, Folder 592)
          - "Hand-Washers or Foot-Washers", 1986 March 9 (Box 26, Folder 593)
          - "The Eternal Rider", 1986 March 23 (Box 26, Folder 594)
          - "Christ in Vivo", 1986 March 30 (Box 26, Folder 595)
          - "Do You Love Me?", 1986 April 13 (Box 26, Folder 596)
            See also: Accession 2004-M-056, 1916-2003 Box 28
          - "The Only Commandment", 1986 April 20 (Box 26, Folder 597)
          - "The Great Bequest", 1986 April 27 (Box 26, Folder 598)
          - "For the World to Survive", 1986 May 4 (Box 26, Folder 599)
            See also: Accession 2004-M-056, 1916-2003 Box 29
          - "Mother O' Mine", 1986 May 11 (Box 26, Folder 600)
          - "Accepting Our Acceptance", 1986 May 18 (Box 26, Folder 601)
          - "Sounding Through", 1986 May 25 (Box 26, Folder 602)
          - "And Now Abide Faith, Hope, Love...", 1986 July 6 (Box 26, Folder 603)
          - "Three Saving Truths", 1986 July 20 (Box 26, Folder 604)
            See also: Accession 2004-M-056, 1916-2003 Box 30U
          - "To Receive a Child", 1986 July 27 (Box 26, Folder 605)
          - "Let Me Receive My Sight" [location uncertain], 1986 September 21 (Box 26, Folder 606)
          - "Nourishing Ourselves", 1986 September 28 (Box 26, Folder 607)
          - "Why I Became a Minister", 1986 October 5 (Box 26, Folder 608)
            See also: Accession 2004-M-056, 1916-2003 Box 31
          - "A Church like it Oughta Be", 1986 October 12 (Box 26, Folder 609)
          - "What the Lord Requires of Us", 1986 October 19 (Box 26, Folder 610)
          - "Spirituality", 1986 October 26 (Box 27, Folder 611)
          - "The Saints", 1986 November 2 (Box 27, Folder 612)
            See also: Accession 2004-M-056, 1916-2003 Box 32
          - "Continue in the Truth...", 1986 November 9 (Box 27, Folder 613)
            See also: Accession 2004-M-056, 1916-2003 Box 33
          - "A Neighborhood as Wide as God's Heart", 1986 November 23 (Box 27, Folder 614)
            See also: Accession 2004-M-056, 1916-2003 Box 34
          - "The Promise of an Unpromising World", 1986 November 30 (Box 27, Folder 615)
            See: Accession 2004-M-056, 1916-2003 Box 35
          - "The Fear of Christmas", 1986 December 7 (Box 27, Folder 616)
          - "The Rebirth of Hope, the Hope of Rebirth", 1986 December 21 (Box 27, Folder 617)
            See also: Accession 2004-M-056, 1916-2003 Box 37
          - "Two Meditations: New Year's Eve & Epiphany", 1986 December 31, 1987 January 4 (Box 27, Folder 618)
            See also: Accession 2004-M-056, 1916-2003 Box 38 See also: Accession 2004-M-056, 1916-2003 Box 39
          - "The Beginning", 1987 January 11 (Box 27, Folder 619)
            See also: Accession 2004-M-056, 1916-2003 Box 40
          - Untitled, "Last night we talked about creation stories, the beginning of the universe, of the world, the first human beings..." [probably Riverside, but location uncertain], 1987 January 25 (Box 27, Folder 620)
            See also: Accession 2004-M-056, 1916-2003 Box 41
          - Untitled, "Last night we left Adam and Eve outside the garden gate...", 1987 February 1 (Box 27, Folder 621)
            See also: Accession 2004-M-056, 1916-2003 Box 42
          - Untitled, "The Roman centurion had to lead Jesus, the crowd and the two thieves out of town to the place called the skull, because capital punishment was not allowed within the walls of Jerusalem..." [probably Riverside, but location uncertain], 1987 April 17 (Box 27, Folder 622)
          - Untitled, "M. Scott Peck - sounds like an organist: T. Tersius Noble, E. Power Biggs - but, as many of you know he is a psychiatrist, and in his book The Road Less Travelled the most important sentence may well be the first, which reads "Life is difficult!", 1987 November 1
            See: Accession 2004-M-056, 1916-2003 Folder 202
          - Untitled, "Heidi Campbell and Ruth Hermann, and some of the rest of you, will surely remember that only months after World War II ended...", 1987 November 29 (Box 27, Folder 623)
        - "Where Does the Heart Go to School" [Harkness Chapel, Connecticut College-with program and related materials], 1990 January 28 (Box 27, Folder 624)
        - Untitled [notes probably for sermon], [1991?] (Box 27, Folder 625)
        - Untitled [Unitarian Church of All Souls-with prayer], 1991 January 6 (Box 27, Folder 626)
        - "You are the Salt of the Earth" [First Church, Cambridge, Massachusetts], 1991 September 15 (Box 27, Folder 627)
        - Undated sermons
          - "A Certain Man had Two Sons" (Box 27, Folder 628)
          - Christmas sermons and notes probably for sermons (Box 27, Folder 629)
          - Untitled [on being conscientious-portion] (Box 27, Folder 630)
          - Untitled [criticizing scholars-portion] (Box 27, Folder 631)
          - Untitled [on education-portions of 2 sermons] (Box 27, Folder 632 - 633)
          - "Education for Growth-Not Gain" (Box 27, Folder 634)
          - Untitled [on the job of a minister-portion] (Box 27, Folder 635)
          - Untitled [on the paralytic] (Box 27, Folder 636 - 637)
          - [Pentecost sermons] (Box 27, Folder 638)
          - "Spirituality and an Alternative Security" (Box 27, Folder 639)
          - Untitled [on violence] (Box 27, Folder 640)
          - Yale
            - "Feed my Sheep" (Box 27, Folder 641)
            - Untitled [on Hebrew laws and ownership] (Box 27, Folder 642)
            - Untitled (Box 27, Folder 643)
          - [Unidentified sermons, portions of sermons, or notes for sermons] (Box 27, Folder 644 - 652)
    - Essays and articles
      - "The 1990s: They Could be Spectacular," Christianity and Crisis, 1990 January 8 (Box 16, Folder 227)
      - Baccalaureate prayer, Yale Alumni Magazine, 1975 June (Box 16, Folder 228)
      - "Caring about Central America" [with related correspondence], 1983, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 229 - 231)
      - "Civil Disobedience, the Draft and the War," Christianity and Crisis, 1968 February 5 (Box 17, Folder 232)
      - "Civilization", undated (Box 17, Folder 233)
      - "Coffin on...," Yale Daily News [3 part series on Vietnam], 1972 October (Box 17, Folder 234)
      - "Coffin on Leave: An Activist Chaplain Spends a Pacific Year Away from Yale," Yale Alumni Magazine, 1974 December (Box 17, Folder 235)
      - Commencement invocations, Yale Alumni Magazine
        - 1970 Jul (Box 17, Folder 236)
        - 1972 Aug (Box 17, Folder 237)
      - "Community and International Violence: Disarmament Begins at Home" [co-authored with Steven Brion-Meisels], undated (Box 17, Folder 238)
      - "From Generation to Generation", 1968 October 20 (Box 17, Folder 239)
      - "From the Prayers of William Sloane Coffin Jr. at the Riverside Church", 1985 (Box 17, Folder 240)
      - "Glasnost, Where Next?", undated (Box 17, Folder 241)
      - "Going in After the Bombers," Newsday [3 part series], [1972] (Box 17, Folder 242)
      - "Gulf War: Wrong Before, During, and After," Christianity and Crisis, 1991 March 4 (Box 17, Folder 243)
      - "The Hartford Debate," Christianity and Crisis [written with Richard Neuhaus and Harvey Cox], 1975 July 21 (Box 17, Folder 244)
      - "Hear Us," Village Voice, 1975 December (Box 17, Folder 245)
      - "It's a Sin to Build a Nuclear Weapon," The Arms Race & Us [from a conference at Riverside Church], 1981 November 15-16 (Box 17, Folder 246)
      - Letters to the editor, undated (Box 17, Folder 247)
      - "Loving Enemies"?, 1980s? (Box 17, Folder 248)
      - "Making the Military Budget Fit the Need," Boston Globe, 1988 September 2 (Box 17, Folder 249)
      - "A Message to the Churches", undated (Box 17, Folder 250)
      - "Messianism or Maturity", undated (Box 17, Folder 251)
      - "The Mideast Crisis", [ca. 1991] (Box 17, Folder 252)
      - "Not Yet a Good Man," New York Times, 1973 June 19 (Box 17, Folder 253)
      - "Personal Salvation," Harper's, 1974 August (Box 17, Folder 254)
      - "Preface to the Riverside Church History of Disarmament Program", 1990 August (Box 17, Folder 255)
      - "Pre-Summit Thoughts" [op-ed to The New York Times ], [1991?] (Box 17, Folder 256)
      - "Report on September Africa Journey", 1986 September 28 (Box 17, Folder 257)
      - [Review of a book about Attica prison], [1975-1976?] (Box 17, Folder 258)
      - "Statement" [on Paris Treaty of 1973], 1975 April 8 (Box 17, Folder 259)
      - "Statement, Perspectives on Shockley", 1975 April 17 (Box 17, Folder 260)
      - "A Student's Report," Et Veritas, 1949 February (Box 17, Folder 261)
      - "Testimony on Ratification of the INF Treaty..." [for SANE/FREEZE], 1988 February 22 (Box 17, Folder 262)
        - "'A Wonderful, Terrible, Beautiful World,'" Duke Alumni Register, 1979 November-December (Box 17, Folder 270)
      - "There's Hope," There's Hope, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 263)
      - "To the Class of '69," [ Boston Globe ?], [1965?] (Box 17, Folder 264)
      - "Wanted in 1972: The Truth," Yale Alumni Magazine, 1972 January (Box 17, Folder 265)
      - "Who Else Will Go to St. Augustine", [1964 Mar] (Box 17, Folder 266)
      - "The Whole Creation Will Be Set Free", 1968 September 22 (Box 17, Folder 267)
      - "Why are the Clergy Concerned about Vietnam?", 1965 (Box 17, Folder 268)
      - "Why Yale Chaplain Rode: Christians Can't be Outside," Life, 1961 June 2 (Box 17, Folder 269)
      - "Your New Self-Image," Vogue, 1972 June (Box 17, Folder 271)
      - Unidentified, miscellaneous [possibly by other authors], undated (Box 17, Folder 272 - 275)
    - Interviews
      - "Yale Reports"
        - 1959 Dec (Box 18, Folder 276)
        - 1962 Jan 14 (Box 18, Folder 277)
      - Playboy [with notes in margin], 1968 August (Box 18, Folder 278)
      - The New Journal, "After the Right On's" [interview by David Sleeper and Patrick Hamilton], 1974 October 1 (Box 18, Folder 279)
      - Transition, "Divining a New Approach to an International Order", 1975 October (Box 18, Folder 280)
      - Family Circle [interview by Linda Dannenburg], 1976 June (Box 18, Folder 281)
      - The Open Mind, "A Man for All Seasons", 1986 July 19 (Box 18, Folder 282)
      - Interview by Pearl Kane [and related correspondence], [1990 Mar], 1990 June 5 (Box 18, Folder 283)
      - Interview by Mark Oppenheimer, 1996 January 6-7 (Box 18, Folder 284)
    - Notes
      - On Amos, undated (Box 18, Folder 285)
      - "Art of Biblical Preaching" [notes], undated (Box 18, Folder 286)
      - On atomic weapons and disarmament, undated (Box 18, Folder 287)
      - Conference notes, undated (Box 18, Folder 288)
      - "God is Love," "Jesus' Duality," and "Anxiety and Sin", undated (Box 18, Folder 289)
      - "Modern Philosophy & Christianity" [notes: possibly from a course of that title], n.y. April-May (Box 18, Folder 290)
      - "Naturalness of Prayer", undated (Box 18, Folder 291)
      - "Niebuhr con't", n.y. May 19 (Box 18, Folder 292)
      - Notes and phone numbers from notebook, undated (Box 18, Folder 293)
      - For books and/or speeches, undated (Box 18, Folder 294)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 18, Folder 295)
    - Prayers, 1954-1983, undated (Box 18, Folder 296 - 305)
    - Quotations
      - By Coffin: "Quotable Quotes from WSC Notebooks" [and related correspondence], 1990 November 26 (Box 18, Folder 306)
      - By others: miscellaneous, 1978 October 13 (Box 18, Folder 307)
    - Speeches
      - Untitled [at alumni luncheon], 1949 February 22 (Box 27, Folder 653)
      - "Eye Hath Not Seen..." [reprint in Et Veritas ], 1949 October 2 (Box 27, Folder 654)
      - Untitled [given at Hillel meeting], 1958 December 12 (Box 27, Folder 655)
      - [Introductory remarks to Yale freshmen-including correspondence], 1959-1974, undated (Box 27, Folder 656)
      - "Is Christianity Necessary?" [a public discussion with Paul Weiss-transcript and Yale News and Review reprint], 1960, 1962 September (Box 27, Folder 657)
      - "Commencement Address" [at the George School], 1964 June 10 (Box 27, Folder 658)
      - "On Civil Disobedience" [for Washington seminar], 1967 February 21 (Box 27, Folder 659)
      - Untitled [at the University of Massachusetts], 1968 November 24 (Box 27, Folder 660)
      - "Resurrection May be a Demand" [Radcliffe College commencement address], 1969 June 11 (Box 27, Folder 661)
      - Untitled [on Memorial Day], [post 1970?] (Box 28, Folder 662)
      - [Hanoi trip press conferences], 1972 (Box 28, Folder 663)
      - Untitled [at the Foote School], 1973 (Box 28, Folder 664)
      - "Evangelism and Social Prophecy" [in Atlanta], [1973 January 15] (Box 28, Folder 665)
      - "A World for All of Us: A Proposal" [Cincinnati General Assembly of the Christian Church (Disciples of Christ)], 1973 October 27 (Box 28, Folder 666)
      - [On world hunger], [1974] (Box 28, Folder 667)
      - "The Spiral of Violence" [Memorial Church, Stanford University], 1974 May 3 (Box 28, Folder 668)
      - "A Harsh and Inescapable Reality" [speech delivered 1975 Jan], 1975 March-April (Box 28, Folder 669)
      - "Northfield" [Seabury House], 1975 April (Box 28, Folder 670)
      - Untitled [at Columbia University Baccalaureate], 1975 May 11 (Box 28, Folder 671)
      - Untitled [commencement address at Union Theological Seminary, Richmond, Virginia], 1976 May 16 (Box 28, Folder 672)
      - "National Security and the Arms Race" [Thomas Merton Lecture, Columbia University], 1980 October 16 (Box 28, Folder 673)
      - Untitled [on disarmament], 1982 Aug, undated (Box 28, Folder 674)
      - [Speeches and related files on AIDS], 1983-1986 (Box 28, Folder 675)
        See also: Accession 2004-M-009, 1918-1996 Folder 588
      - Untitled [press conference on poverty in the United States-includes correspondence], 1984 December 3-13 (Box 28, Folder 676)
      - Untitled [delivered at "The Federal Budget Debate: A Call for New Priorities," Riverside Church, New York City], 1985 January 13 (Box 28, Folder 677)
      - [Speeches and related materials from Olof Palme Memorial Lecture on Disarmament and Development], 1986 August 7, 1987 January 21 (Box 28, Folder 678)
      - "Columbia Charter Day Oration", 1987 April 13 (Box 28, Folder 679)
      - "The Arms Race and the Human Race: A Religious Look at the Bomb" in Proceedings. Nuclear 'Normality': The Ethics of Annihilation [conference proceedings], 1987 May (Box 28, Folder 680)
      - Untitled [at Brandeis University], 1987 November (Box 28, Folder 681)
      - "Statement to General Secretary Gorbachev" [SANE/FREEZE], 1988 June 2 (Box 28, Folder 682)
      - Untitled [at Outward Bound Conference in Cooperstown, New York-with related materials], 1988 June 14-September 11 (Box 28, Folder 683)
      - Untitled [at 25th anniverary of March on Washington], 1988 March (Box 28, Folder 684)
      - Untitled [at Peace Plaza, Salem, Oregon], [1988 Oct] (Box 28, Folder 685)
      - "Twenty-five Years of Progress: Promises to Fulfill" [SANE/FREEZE], 1988 December 10 (Box 28, Folder 686)
      - Untitled [remarks in Kremlin], [1988 or 1989] (Box 28, Folder 687)
      - Untitled [on domestic policy issues-portion], [post 1989] (Box 28, Folder 688)
      - Untitled [on foreign policy, disarmament, and poverty-portion], [1989?] (Box 28, Folder 689)
      - "Peace Economy", [1989] (Box 28, Folder 690)
      - Untitled [on United States budget, especially military], [circa 1989] (Box 28, Folder 691)
      - "Speech of May 10" [at seminar, "Meeting Human Needs with a Peace Economy"], 1989 May 10 (Box 28, Folder 692)
      - "A Role for Religion", [late 1980s?] (Box 28, Folder 693)
      - "New Politics for a New World" [SANE/FREEZE], 1990 February 16 (Box 28, Folder 694)
      - [Correspondence regarding a speech in Lakewood, Ohio-contains no actual speech], 1990 April-July (Box 28, Folder 695)
      - "Encampment for Citizenship", 1990 June (Box 28, Folder 696)
      - Untitled [at Silvery Bay, New York-with correspondence regarding speech and related speeches], 1990 September 22 (Box 28, Folder 697)
      - Untitled [on Professor Brand Blanchard], 1990 October 29 (Box 28, Folder 698)
      - "All Souls", [circa 1991] (Box 28, Folder 699)
      - "The Dangers of Self-Righteousness", [circa 1991] (Box 28, Folder 700)
        See also: Accession 2004-M-056, 1916-2003 Folder 217
      - Untitled [on the first Gulf War], [ca. 1991] (Box 28, Folder 701)
      - Untitled [on foreign policy, especially in the Middle East portion], [circa 1991] (Box 28, Folder 702)
      - "Iraq", [circa 1991] (Box 28, Folder 703)
      - "Keeping the Faith", [1991?] (Box 28, Folder 704)
      - Untitled [on Middle East and domestic issues], [circa 1991] (Box 28, Folder 705)
      - Untitled [on Middle East and Islam], [circa 1991 Jan] (Box 28, Folder 706)
      - "Address" [SANE/FREEZE-in Chicago], 1991 August 9-11 (Box 28, Folder 707)
      - "Welcoming Remarks" [SANE/FREEZE-in Chicago], 1991 August 9 (Box 28, Folder 708)
      - "Lessons of the Gulf War-What Next?" [parts I & II-at Christian Conference of Connecticut], 1991 September 28 (Box 28, Folder 709)
      - "Tulsa, Oklahoma", 1991 October 24-25 (Box 28, Folder 710)
      - "The Pastor as Spiritual Leader" [at the United Church of Christ Consultation on Parish Ministry, Orlando, FL], 1992 January 6-10 (Box 29, Folder 711)
        See also: Accession 2004-M-056, 1916-2003 Folder 290
      - Untitled [at Plymouth Church, Shake Heights, Ohio], 1992 May 18-20 (Box 29, Folder 712)
      - "Art of Risking"
        See: Accession 2004-M-056, 1916-2003 Folder 220
      - "Ben Spock Intro", Undated (Box 29, Folder 713)
      - "Community or Chaos", Undated (Box 29, Folder 714)
      - "Death Penalty" [notes, probably for speech], Undated (Box 29, Folder 715)
      - "Dedication of the Allard K. Lowenstein Square", Undated (Box 29, Folder 716)
      - "Divorce" [notes, probably for speech], Undated (Box 29, Folder 717)
      - "Does Higher Education Make Human Beings More Human?" [notes, probably for speech], Undated (Box 29, Folder 718)
      - Untitled [on fasting], Undated (Box 29, Folder 719)
      - "Happy Thanksgiving, Dear Friends", Undated (Box 29, Folder 720)
      - "Ideals and Ambition" [notes probably for speech], Undated (Box 29, Folder 721)
      - "Jesus Christ is Risen Today, Alleluia", Undated (Box 29, Folder 722)
      - "Kicking the Cold War Habit", Undated (Box 29, Folder 723)